so I'm teaching this steps of the path
the plan is about 15 year plan we've
what 50 yeah not with how you say for
sure
male 15 sir how does a 50 not whoosh -
voiceover sir su we finish about eight
years then many people didn't come at
the beginning so I'm reviewing the
earlier years okay
everyday I will do a little bit from the
earlier year so you got some paper
tonight when you came in
that's to help you review so in the
evening I will do review some review of
the old classes okay okay so let's start
the first page has a dog and we start on
the next page has a car salesman
okay selling the car to the couple so
the way I like to review the old
material from eight years is I like to
do it with pictures pictures are easy to
remember okay
I call it it them idea
image then it's supposed to be easy way
to remember also the new material we
have pictures then you can test your own
understanding
you cover the letters with your hand and
you look at the picture and you try to
remember what's the meaning okay so
tomorrow I will teach you the meaning of
the first six pictures
from the past years classes then
starting tomorrow we will have
examination I will pick one name from
the student list and I will give you a
microphone and you will have chance to
embarrass yourself with 500 other people
okay
so Tim tomorrow I'll need a way to
choose names okay if you want you to
take your name out okay give Tim $100
[Music]
throw out your name okay Tim I get 50
you get 50 okay real real business okay
now the first pictures name the first
species number he's r109
okay we did already 108 okay I I started
this review last year okay so if you
want the first hundred and eight we can
give you the file online Tim it's okay
we can give the file first hundred and
eight items for the view
okay it's okay oh oh it's on the
knowledgebase website it's free it's
free okay okay so I'm starting one
online okay the picture is a guy's
selling a car to the couple
[Music]
and in English we call used-car salesman
it's actually a little bit bad word in
America
CEO buy this car the last owner was 80
years old she only drive the car once a
month to go to the church this car
almost like new then they will talk a
lot and you will buy the car it will
break next week okay we call used-car
salesmen their talk is very good you
will buy the car it means in English we
say good sales job after you talk to
them you want to buy the car ok so while
I put the picture here in this lamb rim
tradition
okay steps of the path okay
it's thousand years old all all the Jing
200,000 Jing put in one booth so we are
saving this Jing in many countries we we
did a catalog already catalog is about
actually if you three hundred and twenty
thousand books three hundred and twenty
thousand books
okay we found three hundred and twenty
thousand books Mongolia Russia Nepal
India we found the book now we are
typing okay I think it would take five
generation just the typing
okay and all of those books contained in
one book it's called Lam Meem
this is what you are studying lumpam
means number one do this number two do
this number three do this number four do
this okay don't need to think a lot just
to step step step step if you start the
class here and you just come every year
next year Bali
super beautiful right I went there this
year my Singapore friends kidnapped me
[Music]
we went to Bali we had VIP teaching and
I thought wow this is even more
beautiful than tyrant so Jazmin agree
and next year we go to Bali
okay okay agree okay
okay so here is the Buddhahood Nippon
and Buddhahood here is me here is us
then this book just - one two three four
five finish okay don't have to think too
much just come Valley Thailand Thailand
Polly Polly Polly Polly Polly
[Music]
hawaii's then you know Buddhahood Hawaii
very close to Buddhahood okay then a
disco one by one okay then in the
beginning of Lamia the lamrim car sales
man he will do what I'm doing now
[Music]
ah this guy so beautiful
shit - one two three four okay you can
reach the Buddhahood
it's easy okay like that so it's
traditional in Buddhism before you study
anything the teacher must do sales job
oh you you see cooking you can see 500
years into future okay what you are
doing 500 years from now you can see you
can see every person in the world in 20
minutes and you can have love direct
love for each person in the world seven
billion people in 20 minutes
[Music]
one by one in 20 minutes
cool so that's called sales job okay in
the beginning of Lamia
teacher's job self jump you studied this
not me you're gonna be a Buddha soon
okay so don't just teach first tell the
people what's so cool then they will get
hungry yeah me teach me why am I telling
you this
my learning teaching job halfway
finished
I have about five six more years then
it's your job
to continue next generation I don't have
to do that dance tonight I already did
I gave to next generation okay I
understand so you have to do next okay
so before you teach tell the people why
cool why it's cool if you learn to
meditate okay if business come sit
closer yeah okay she had trouble to hear
me because I talk like this that's it
yeah we do business programs
you know then we teach people meditation
they say I don't want to learn
meditation like in Russia there they say
I'm not Buddhist I'm Christian I just
want to do business why I have to learn
team country why I have to learn
meditation if this person learns
meditation good meditation they can see
next year's new product this year okay
they can see next year's iPhone this
year
[Music]
if they are in the stock market they can
see which stock go up next year if you
meditate a lot so you have to do sales
job to the businessmen you want to
meditate no I'm not Buddhist yeah but do
you understand if you meditate every day
you can see we start going up next year
I think I like to meditate okay so you
have to sell the Lamia okay and the
meditation it's a Buddhist tradition to
get the student excited now in the
beginning about this path I had one guy
came to me when I come to your program
it's many many many many ideas many many
things to think about
[Music]
I just want to use my heart I don't want
to this the five steps of emptiness or
you know all this conching I just want
to use my heart in this tradition you
cannot open your heart without your mind
[Music]
okay understanding come first
okay ten ten understanding without pen
understanding you cannot love you cannot
open your heart okay
why like a husband if your husband is
yelling at you at home then you feel
angry after you study the pen
okay before you study the pen you are
angry at the husband if the husband
yelling after you study the pen who you
angry at me okay I understand
so you cannot really love the husband
without conscience
you cannot love other person if you
don't understand senior in this
tradition okay you cannot love the
husband if you don't understand
who made him okay understand
so in this tradition we we think to open
the heart okay you can really open the
heart to your husband if you understand
his life depends if you think husband is
angry person you will never have perfect
marriage not possible you will have
truth in the war merit truth means truth
means agreement to stop the fighting for
a while okay if you don't understand who
made the husband
it's impossible to have perfect match
okay perfect marriages go perfect
marriage is most beautiful thing in this
world okay but it's not possible it's a
part impossible if you don't understand
where husband come from one lady came to
me
guess not I need your help one
so I'm married to my husband for 30
years then no I'm Chinese person in in
China the wife should cook I understand
I'm not complaining I enjoy cooking for
my family I can take that responsibility
dance but in 30 years cooking for my
husband
he never washed the dish one time then
is there some way I can change him with
this seed system okay
then I taught her first step okay I want
my husband to what I did I should find
karmic partner I should help my friend
who has too much work in their home lots
of coffee meditation I taught her the
first time next year I went back to her
country she said yes I come to my house
for dinner I have something to show you
and I went to her house and they're a
beautiful house I'm not going to tell
you which city because you will guess
the person then there's a big table
she said sit down there's nothing on the
table except a small Bell she said I
want to show you something
and she pick up the bell bbbbb
then kitchen door open her husband come
out
he has woman's apron then he's like this
she's the dinner ready not yet a whole
finish thank ok you go then he went in
the kitchen
then she look at me Gingka I said what
happened
she said you taught me I said I taught
you how to wash the dish he'll get to
wash the dish yeah I guess nah
this took only two months
I do four steps for two months he start
to wash the dishes then I'm thinking why
should I stop here I can also use the
four steps he will cook there I didn't
now he's cooking no fighting no
discussion she did not ask him to cook
she did not ask him to wash the dishes
because he come from her seats then you
husband have to do you have to follow
your seeds understand now I can say just
have love go home have love tell your
husband I love you why can you wash a
dish some time then start big war
understand so in the seed system husband
is pen come from you change changed here
see husband will change okay now
tomorrow night 9:15 after this class
I will have special class $500 to come
only men can come how to plant the seed
to never wash the dishes okay
[Applause]
you want to go deeper yeah let's go
deeper you saw the movie Titanic yeah so
that was the biggest ship in the world
and it was new that's the first time
they use it
then here's Titanic coming then here is
iceberg mountain of ice if the ship hit
the iceberg big problem understand the
iceberg is the wife's seeds in her mind
the Titanic is the man's seed in his
mind this iceberg is husband have seed
to wash the dishes
[Music]
the ship is woman has a seed to worship
dishes who will win husband state or
wife see which city stronger no
impossible then no one will wash the
dishes can I be born
okay
somebody has to wash the dishes right
it's impossible husband has said not to
water dishes the husband has a seed not
not to wash the dishes the wife has said
not to wash the dishes
somebody has to wash the dishes probably
they will invite getting Michael to come
and wash the dishes right woman seed has
to be more powerful or Manson has to be
more powerful yeah both both can both
can be true in the kitchen of the
husband the wife is washing the dishes
in the kitchen of the wife the husband
was that they teach the how can be two
kitchens in one kitchen
understand okay under stairs can be pen
can be cheat on May 20 okay I'm cleaning
okay okay okay okay
so we finished the first row in this
system real love has understanding okay
I love my husband and I work on my seeds
and I improved my husband okay and and
the husband also improved the why
there's harmony in the kitchen not you
cannot have love without conscience okay
you have to think about it alright so in
this path it says learning is the path
okay it's the first step you have to
learn the instructions this is our
tradition okay if you learn about the
pen in the class then you use it at home
okay this is Buddhism okay this is our
tradition okay first line then use at
home okay all right that's my sales job
in my house my partner Veronica she
never washes the dishes okay I'm telling
you how I cut my finger cooking also I
made a big mistake I invite her to my
class understand okay there's a small
light okay small light light
yeah so in the world there are many
things to know like you learned about
the pen right I still need your PIN you
have extra extra
you have to ok it's ok it's ok she want
me to advertise her pen ok before you
came to this before you came to my
teaching you you think this is just a
pen and you don't think about it
it doesn't come from me that's it come
from pen if someone ask you does the pen
come from you or a pen come from pin you
will say I don't care I just use it
I don't care pen cut some pen can't come
from me then you teach them if you find
out where the pen comes from your
husband will do the daisies forever
I'll teach me the pen teach me about
their pen then someone teach you about
the pen before they teach you about the
pen this is a kind of darkness
where this pen come from it's like
darkness then someone teach you about
the dog and the pen and a new light
comes in your mind there are billions of
darkness in the world there are billion
things you don't know okay
but now one of them became a life
okay so Buddhism teaching make life
makes life make life make life make like
make like whole life okay got it
in the beginning this is for you this is
darkness nobody taught you about this in
the school your parents didn't talk
about this then you come here that
darkness become light then if you come
Tyler each time you come new new light
okay new lights in the month that's what
we are doing okay that's the meaning of
this picture
okay cool can you hear okay it's okay
okay all right hey but then I don't talk
to those people
okay although it's okay all right next
picture hundred dollars somebody no
teachers can answer this picture is
called the ultimate portable well who
can explain to me hundred dollars I'm
sorry I told her you guys have a
microphone
and you'll give me $200 if you're wrong
I can make some business by the way I'm
looking for two things the answer has
two parts $50 and $50 okay
[Music]
this picture is called the ultimate
portable well portable in English means
you can carry it mala is portable you
can carry Tesla is not portable too
heavy
[Music]
sometimes if the answer is too long it's
usually well that's a nice answer but
not to this question okay somebody else
you choose you just then they don't
fight with me sometimes choose in the
back okay
Deutschland two parts to the answer I
mean you can be DCI teacher if you give
this entry
just have to give unique any question
you can say I think you need to use the
first thing okay let's go to learn to
part
[Music]
nope okay one more one more we have to
finish tonight
[Music]
you don't need anything to share his
wisdom so that's why it is portable okay
that's a beginning of that you go ahead
[Music]
I'll tell you a joke I went to a nice
restaurant in shinjang with my friends
several nights ago nights ago then
there's a one bath bathroom on this side
one bathroom on this time and there's a
big time men's bathroom this way women's
bathroom this way underneath the sign
men have to go to the left
why woman is always right
very funny so his wife gave pretty good
answer the woman is right but not not
not enough okay two things
okay number one what you learn in this
class you will always have here you can
carry it everywhere if there's a war
tomorrow you know world war you lose
your house you cannot go back home you
have to stay in Thailand the rest of
your lives then you lost everything your
car home bank account family but what
you learn in this class you can never
lose no one can take it from you this is
the only sure property you can keep it
learn things which you can keep here
bank account can fail country can fail
everything can fail you can lose your
arm but this idea no one can take from
you
you will always have it's safe second
part of the answer it's the only thing
you can take with you when you die okay
you cannot take a body you cannot take
family you cannot even take your name
but these ideas they will stay in your
mind it's its wealth precious like
diamond and most portable if there's if
they destroy the whole world you can
keep it and if you die you can take it
with you
cool that's a good answer
[Applause]
[Music]
okay you have to give Geshe Michael $100
just kidding just kidding he's cousin by
the way if you have Rory you want me to
bless and you can put up here after
after the pogroms every day
every day you can bring up here and
maybe we can add one more table here
okay
we have about 15 minutes right it's the
next performance ready right in 15
minutes okay all right good okay
next picture 112 then there's an English
idiom it comes from a famous play by
Shakespeare
I think okay
or maybe Goethe gotta from Germany
guitar very famous I forget anyway
some guy want to buy I forget he wants
to buy success or something this
powerful being told him I can get for
you
[Music]
but I need one pound of your flesh you
have to cut one pound from somewhere I
will cut from here I think I have a
little bit a little bit extra here okay
so they say okay give me one pound of
your flesh then he did it because this
is some kind of magic he can get his
success for rest of his life and there's
a beautiful story stout data and stout
dasa he was a crazy guy he loves to kill
people and eat them okay and he lives in
a cave and he he he goes out and he
finds people and he kidnapped them and
eat them
[Music]
then people know about him this is like
2000 years ago in India if they see him
everybody will run he's very powerful
then there was a prince whose heart is
very pure and won one day
stardancer came to the palace and he's
going to take two or three people take
them then there's a wonderful prince
with a pure heart he was studying some
lamb rib in the palace you know and
thought that's I came he grabbed two
three people then the prince said came
to him no fear everyone else run away
then the Prince said if you need to eat
somebody you take me these are innocent
people don't bother them
that's his thing yeah you look pretty
tasty
then he took him to his cave then put
him down you know start to make the fire
you know then the prince start to cry
good translation then south thousand I
you are supposed to be Prince of this
country
[Music]
you supposed to be brave person you're
crying you're gonna die I'm gonna cook
you dinner princess what are you talking
about
you're crazy yeah I'm crying why are you
crying you're afraid of me I'm not
afraid of you why are you crying
you took me from my la même class I
didn't have chance to make offering to
the teacher then you took me from the
class now I will die I didn't have
chance to thank my teacher I want to
thank my teachers then the princess I
have idea the prince said to the monster
okay just let me go for half hour okay I
will go back to the palace I have to
thank my teacher you know make offering
he taught me only four lines one poem
then you came so I want to go back say
goodbye
thank my teacher then I'll come back you
can eat me the mousseline you think I'm
stupid monster you won't come back then
a prince got angry who you think I am
I have honor I respect the Dharma I'm
not like you I will keep my word
you are killing people eating people I'm
not like you I keep my word have honor
then the master said yesterday where did
your father go your father go he went
out on the horse
why hunting huh
your father also killed things
yeah is this a good no I'm also killing
what's the difference you Prince you
came you eat me I also admit you are
same as me
the prince is like no you are worth why
you eat people
okay that's a worse monster said okay
I'm curious to see if you will come back
you know I think you won't come back
okay then you go I will make the fire
bigger you know you go to your teacher
thank you the teacher say goodbye I will
wait for you let's see if you come back
I'm curious so he Prince went back it's
a very famous offering he paid 1000 gold
coin for each line
like Sashi Pookie tomato time
he paid ten to one thousand gold then
each each each line he gave ten thousand
peace of God then he said teacher I'm
sorry I have to go I will not come back
and I love you I hope next life we can
suppose then his father said where you
going I promised to go back to the
barbecue then the father said you're
crazy you don't have to keep promise to
this person how are you gonna be king
you are not good politicians the King
has to be smart you know King has to
make a promise but if the promise is not
good you can change it perfect
[Music]
how can you run the country if you are
so honest
then the prints end that's not good King
Good King keeps a word even to the
monster king will keep the word I'm
going then he went back then her
monsters like you came back I promise
you I keep my promise you're a strange
then the princess okay I'm ready cook me
monster got angry this is my house I
decide when to eat I will decide when to
cook you what did guide teach you there
you want to go bad
what that guy teacher said well he
taught me special verse
can you teach to me okay I'll teach you
the meaning of the verse even if you
have to cut your flesh pay one pound
flesh for four lines it's worth it okay
that's the verse then the monsters like
then took off his he has a cloth around
his chest put on the stone today Prince
you teach me you know you're good
teacher then he start to learn Dhamma
the monster later he thought come chief
director okay cool three okay so it
means it's a valuable thing Dhamma is
valuable thing even if you have to pay a
lot of money for the airplane ticket to
Hawaii
don't hesitate okay
it's worth it okay don't hesitate there
are people who cut their arm for this
[Music]
spent time seventeen years walking to
get this teaching you had seventeen
hours okay
three hours in the airplane 14 hours in
the customs
and a one-hour to drive it right it's
not so bad okay I I don't know about you
I spend like three hours of minutes okay
number one one three pictures dog this
is talking about the relationship
between the teacher and the student okay
what should the relationship be in the
lamrim tradition it's okay there's a
kind of fake respect okay student like
you know and they bow like this many
times and they they said don't touch a
large everybody move Mouse is coming
and then I'll also come you know like
this and everybody I served my teacher
for 30 years I'm his cook dishwashers I
do his laundry you know everything then
I saw hundreds and hundreds of students
[Music]
this one get out the way so it's been
you know then they make everybody
nervous nobody likes it this kind of
student hit my teacher he's you get back
the teacher copy but don't touch his
chair what do you do what do you think
you're doing you know I saw many many
like that student then I saw that other
kind Lama comes in hey you want some tea
yeah Remy to make a beautiful team thank
you TTE
so cool
your class is so fun make me happy then
you know like a llama is a favorite dog
and the student is like I like you we
call in English affection okay it's
different from respect different from
respect
okay respect is a little bit artificial
[Music]
you know then the affection I had so
much fun since you taught me the pen my
husband is so much better you feel like
my favorite dog
okay that's a different feeling okay
supposed to think that teacher is Buddha
Buddha came to the tiler
then supposed to respect like Buddha but
there's two ways to respect one is
respect from the mouth you know then
make everyone uncomfortable then the
other respect like jig main where are
you she's my personal assistant for 25
years you know and we have respect real
respect okay like pick up your tea I
will start to drink the chocolate this
is like gasps I love you
no chocolate
we need to put a live long time I love
you you cannot have chocolates dancer
I'm a teacher you have to respect me no
affection I love you I want you to stay
no chocolate okay like that see
different feel different right
it's a affection it's a kind of love
it's better than respect it's a higher
kind of respect she treat me like pet
dog before I come up here she's not try
to look like a llama okay I can sit up
straight
okay this is the affection okay then
that's a real mom in student this damn
is so cool it's not like okay not like
that okay gotta feel the difference
so tradition in in our line the
unmeaning gala gathered at or do you
mean you're guilty to another topic so
what doesn't think you usually thought
we have a mind and number like our all
to remember I'm 43 I think you are 44
okay your student have to memorize your
name thousand years from now Gallagher a
gallery I guess it to another Edmund
total like that there will be no your
name will be in the line then we have
respect okay you are the next teacher
okay our lineage not very cold
not very respect
okay we are like half like in at all are
you sure you know they're like cool okay
and have fun - okay inside like Tonka
you know see my dad good talk good show
yeah your TV another Jake yes it on our
division so this shop like that mine is
sharp
behavior like a dog affection okay I
understand
okay this is your family
we are jarring now we are dren okay our
family's tradition for a thousand years
is friendly happy have fun Shenzhen
China stopped our dancing Dharma sharp
correct 2000 books okay sharp okay but
they're feeling like dog okay understand
this is respect real respect real
respect is affection
cool okay thank you let's do one more
picture okay and then we'll do question
and answer
this is the last half hour it's free if
you need PP go okay if you need just go
okay we are relaxed okay just a punk
song
relax jaha okay just question answer but
my job I have to finish one more this
week comes hundred dollars I taught it
many times
Steve's ready Steve Steve raised his
hand first he's a teacher microphone
here here no Steve Steve head first
okay now my manga clearly in Buddhism
good student should not be like the
three cups okay mom and are clearly
[Music]
thank you shopping okay bye
[Applause]
yeah later
okay okay okay question answer that we
finished six kinds of review okay we had
salesman we had the light we had the
portable well we had even to cut your
skin is worth it we had dog affection
and we had Steve's three cups you have
to know them tomorrow night okay I will
check I will choose name you'll get the
microphone
okay what's the wrong answer
okay am i okay any question so if you
need bathroom break
tea break if you want to go home
secretly
you're welcome okay question time and we
just have about 20 no yeah 20 more
minutes
[Music]
[Applause]
see the
[Music]
okay good question I asked my teacher
this question and that's meaning of
lineage you know when when you become
teacher you could say I heard this from
my teacher okay this is mini so in my
case my father was very big man and he
liked to hunt and he killed many animals
and he killed many fish
he even has a fishing boat for fun he
will take us for fishing big fish in the
ocean
then when I was small I was about seven
years old he will teach us to catch the
fish I also shot deer and he teaches on
this then he teaches to clean the deer
and the fish special knife and you start
here and you cut and then you open then
you you don't eat all of those things
you have to take them out with the deer
you are completely covered with blood
you have to take out other stomach
and it's the first time I did it then I
told my father I cannot do again he got
very angry you are we grew up in the
cowboy place Arizona this is our state
our province custom every young man
shoot deer catch the fish I said I'm
sorry I cannot do very then he got
cancer then the doctor said here I was
with the doctor he said your father
needs special operation
[Music]
what's the operation we will start here
we will cut then I mark you know we will
take some part of his leg will replace
yeah then I'm like I don't know about
karma at that time like that's change
you know exactly same cut we used for
the deer and the fish they thought oh
that's strange you know later my dad got
cancer he had cancer
I was studying Buddhism then I I asked
my teacher my father's time they cannot
they did operation they said they they
open him then they look inside then they
say forget it they just they said you
cannot happen you know so I went to stay
with him in the last few weeks I asked
my teacher this question what can I do
to help my father
and it's like you said number one
there's a very good Christian custom
some Christian when the person is dying
[Music]
you call their priest he will come then
he will ask everyone go outside go
outside and the person is alone with the
priest the priest will ask him you have
any bad thing you want to talk about
then in in Buddhism also if you made a
mistake in your life if you tell someone
it helps to clean it a lot it helps a
lot so and if you say I'm sorry I won't
do again you know it almost destroys the
scene so my teacher told me with your
father first thing see if you can get
him to tell you all the bad then second
thing as you said remind him all the
good things he did
dan you know you taught me always to
respect other people he was pretty good
businessmen you taught me to be honest
to other people you know you taught me
to work hard thank you very much you are
so he was very good with children we
have four brothers and I said you are so
patient with us he never hit me one time
absolutely
so I said you know thank you so these
are the two things one tell them you
want to clean anything sometimes you
have to trick them okay my father is not
religious he will go to the church if my
mother put the robe and bring him he
doesn't like it much so I'm thinking you
know I have to get his confession what
can I do so
he's dying he cannot eat he got very
skinny and then then he he only watch TV
then I watch sit with him watch TV Oh
dad I remember you said you were in the
war yeah you say you kill many people
yeah will you do that again no very bad
then I'll trick him to contrast so he
claimed the scene you know and I talked
with like that so you can do that you
don't have to say it's religion if they
talk about their bad deal
if they say I will not do again that
seed almost finished now last advice if
a person dies for 49 days they are in
possible they are in Bordeaux what's a
bottle feel like for them usually they
forget they are dead okay
then they come to the kitchen you know
and everyone's crying and they're like
why is everyone crying then no one can
hear them in there like standing why are
you crying then everybody ignore them
because cannot see them then they get
upset you are my family why you ignore
me I'm asking question you know and
people ignore them and they get up for
the first hour or something they get
very upset
then they then oh I died then they they
can stay for 49 days possible and they
love you they want to be at home so of
course they are listening to what you
are talking about so it's very cool to
talk about the good things my father did
my teacher calls the bottle time is the
lottery time lottery you are picking
we call sin Depp in The Wheel of Life
link number 8 9 and 10 then at that time
you choose the seed that will choose the
next life then the the Jing word is very
difficult but Jackson Debra then I asked
my teacher I saw it in the Jing what's
the meaning but Jackson he said I will
tell you tomorrow this is the benefit of
staying close to your teacher I will
tell you tomorrow then next day in the
evening he also has a bell
then he will ring the bell
he lives upstairs he's the abbot he has
the only TV in the monastery supposed to
be for learning current events but my
Lama like to watch the news you know
then I when I hear the bell
I have to run upstairs it means there's
something important on the television
then I heard the bell run upstairs say
come on come on this is the answer to
your question what's the question
yesterday you asked me this special word
in the jinx in the death meditation
hears on TV then every night in America
at the same time seven o'clock there
were special TV show very beautiful
woman in a very short miniskirt she
would come out you know on the TV then
there's a special wheel and she will
stop it put her hand inside she will
pick the lottery numbers for the whole
country you know I mean there are like
20 million people waiting you know will
she pick my numbers you know and and my
teacher said that's intestine Depa doing
death in the bottle that person is
picking their lottery number
I mean in this life you did many good
days you did many bad days you have
thousands of seeds but one will decide
the next month some very very important
moment this tip will last for 78 years
will you be will you be human will you
have big nose or small nose American
[Music]
[Laughter]
okay then this is the important moment
so it's very important before they die
you talk about all the good things they
never fight where the person who's dying
who dad who you giving your money to in
my under listen you know I never never
fight with those people everything calm
everything happy talk to them about the
good thing they did in their life after
they die they are listening to you they
are watching you talk to your family do
you remember dad
what the good thing he did he helped
everybody
I remember in 2015 he helped a poor
family give them lots of money you know
we have good father then father time
that's correct
yeah I remember then if the number
lottery number come at that moment you
helped him to have a good River so very
important first seven weeks 49 days the
day of the death is number one if they
die at 11:59 that's still the first day
then for seven weeks very careful in the
families home only talk about the good
things he did because he will listen and
possible that will pick the number ok
last last thing then we go to bed ok
jing-mei I think it was Pat Wells friend
Terry Grier know what her name a woman
whose daughter died Feliciano yeah so
this lady
20 years ago yeah her daughter done her
daughter's only about 20 I think and she
died very young so she came to me she's
completely destroyed her life when the
parent dies it's very hard if the child
died before the parents there's nothing
worse than that she's completely sad
didn't I taught her all this thing talk
talk seven weeks taught talk good about
your daughter all the good things she
did I saw her recently I said so that
was 20 years ago I think she told me
that guess not come here I said what I
still talk to my daughter every night
during the cafe Minchin I talked to her
and it's so beautiful and we have such
beautiful relationship and I'm very
happy I feel very lucky
still I talk to her so you don't have to
stop after seven weeks and you will meet
them again
that's one reason to become Buddha okay
you always meet your family you will be
together again so that is a temporary
separation it's not permanent one reason
to study function is to meet them again
you will be in the same Buddha paradise
together and you'll be super happy okay
so don't worry okay and talk to them and
never fight with your relatives at that
time
just talk about good things
all right solution volunteer leader from
Beijing it's going to lead
[Music]
yes
tonight shake so touchy tsunami shake
[Music]